《超女》前情提要
Previously on Supergirl...
黑暗氪星人女巫们想复活主宰
Dark Kryptonian witches want to resurrect Reign
利用她改造地球环境
and use her to terraform the Earth,
让地球变成新的氪星
turning it into a new Krypton.
利维坦要来了
Leviathan is coming.
你可以走了  玛戈特
You can go, Margot.
当我们重启宇宙后  我们的世界合并了
When we restarted the universe, our worlds combined.
超查部  凯特科  整个纳欣诺市
The DEO, CatCo, all of National City
现在都在这个地球上
is on this Earth now.
莱克斯·卢瑟拿走了《命运之书》
Lex Luthor has the Book of Destiny.
我想着命运可以重写一下
I thought destiny could use a little rewrite.
-人们觉得莱克斯是个好人吗  -他可是老大
- People think Lex is a good guy? - He's the boss!
这个地方是他的
He owns this place.
我们生活在一个前沿的世界
We live in a world on the cutting edge.
随着人类的进步
And as mankind advances,
它所面临的危险也与日俱增
so too does the danger it faces.
多年来  我们秘密地保护着美国
For years, we protected America in secret.
但现在  我们希望你们知道
But now, we want you to know
你们得到了良好的保护
you're in good hands.
我们给予所以人希望  帮助与同情
Hope, help and compassion for all.
-这是我们超查部的...  -座右铭
- That's our motto here at... - The DEO.
如有任何超常需要  请联系我们
Call us for all your extranormal needs.
我快吐了  我才不在乎我们身处哪个世界
Duh! Gag me with a spoon. I don't care what world we're on,
我觉得我永远都不会同意拍那条广告
I can't ever see a version of myself agreeing to do that commercial.
在这个星球上  你和莱克斯是出色的合作伙伴
Well, on this planet, you and Lex were excellent collaborators.
不  停  这简直就是我的噩梦
No, stop! This is literally my nightmare.
你觉得我是什么感觉
Okay, well, how do you think I feel?
我完全被蒙在鼓里
I've been totally in the dark.
谢天谢地  荣恩让我找回了记忆
Thank God J'onn gave me my memories back.
是啊  我希望他能让所有人都找回记忆
Yeah, I know, I wish he could do it for everyone.
根据他的说法  恢复世界的集体记忆
Well, according to him, restoring the world's collective memories
会大规模地重新设定关系
would reconfigure relationships on such a massive scale
使每个人的内心都大受打击
that everyone's minds would literally be blown.
恶心
Ugh, gross.
超查部现在是地狱之口了  就是这样
Well, the DEO is a hellmouth now, so there's that.
-凯特科改变了吗  -仍然是个八卦小报
- Has CatCo changed? - Still a tabloid.
但所有人都着了莱克斯·卢瑟的道
But everyone's on the Lex Luthor train,
这也包括安德里亚  真是太"棒"了
which is great. Including Andrea.
他将获得"明日之人"奖
He's getting some Man of Tomorrow award,
她派我和威廉去报道
and she sent me and William to cover it.
我不敢相信
I... uh, I can't believe
就连威廉都被莱克斯洗脑了
even William is drinking the Lex Kool-Aid.
放他一马吧
Well, you gotta give him a little break, okay.
只有那些已经恢复记忆的人
The only people that know the truth
才知道真相
are the ones whose memories have been restored.
有布莱尼  尼娅  凯莉
So it's Brainy, Nia, Kelly...
所有在危机中伸出援手的英雄们
All the heroes who helped at the Crisis,
也包括某人  这让我气得冒烟
including you know who, which just makes my blood boil.
卢瑟家的人独树一帜
Well, the Luthors are a breed of their own.
是啊  说到这里
Yeah, speaking of which,
我得和莉娜谈谈
I have to talk to Lena.
在这个地球上  莉娜和超女是搭档
Look, on this Earth, Lena and Supergirl are partners.
在我看来
And as far as I'm concerned,
她没有试图对这个星球进行精神控制
she's not trying to mind control the planet.
而且她不恨你
Plus, she doesn't hate you,
所以也许莉娜没有恢复记忆
so maybe Lena not having her memories
是一件好事
is a good thing.
不
No, no.
虽然我很想和莉娜重归于好
As much as I would love to have a clean slate with Lena,
但我有责任把真相告诉她
I owe it to her to tell the truth.
我曾经犯过这个错误  我不会再犯了
I made that mistake once, I'm not going to do it again.
你好啊  瞌睡虫
Hey, there, sleepy head.
我给你煎了两个鸡蛋
I fried a couple of eggs for you.
麻醉剂残留可不是闹着玩的
Methohexital hangovers are no joke.
你一定饿坏了
You must be ravenous.
这不可能是真的
This can't be real.
你死了
You're dead.
所以  你什么都记得
So, you remember everything?
我当然记得  我杀了你
Of course I remember! I killed you!
没错  你杀了我
Yes, that's right, you killed me.
但那都是过去的事了
But that is all in the past.
因为我回来了
Because I'm back now,
而且我原谅了你
and I forgive you.
你在说什么  发生了什么
What are you talking about? What is happening?
发生了...某种危机
Well, it was, uh... sort of a Crisis.
是一种...反物质波
It was an... antimatter wave.
-是的  -我和艾丽克斯合作
- Ah, yes. - Alex and I worked together.
-嗯  -我们建了一个传送门
- Mmm-hmm. - We built a portal...
反物质波还是来了吗
The wave still came?
是的  损失了数十亿美元  多元宇宙崩塌了
Yes, and billions were lost and the multi-verse collapsed,
这一切都很有趣
and it was all very interesting.
现在重要的是有个非常强大的人
What matters now is that a very powerful person
让我活过来帮忙
brought me back to life to help.
但我拒绝那样做
But I refused to do so,
除非他答应你会挺过来
unless he promised that you would make it through okay,
如今你活了下来  而且脑袋完好无损
and you have, with your noggin intact.
你为了达到目的  把整个多元宇宙的命运当赌注
You gambled the fate of the entire multi-verse to get your own way?
更棒的是  在这个新世界里
It gets better. In this new world,
我们在卢瑟公司和超查部并肩工作
we work side by side at Luthor Corp and the DEO
让世界变得更美好
to make the world a better place.
所以我在地狱
So I'm in hell.
不  你在一种新的现实中
No, no, you're in a new reality.
对外界来说  我们是亿万富翁慈善家
To the outside world, we're billionaire philanthropists.
这是完美的掩护
It's the perfect cover.
-我不想和你有任何瓜葛  -对  你想要
- I want nothing to do with you. - Ah, yes, you want to
用你的"无害"计划修正人性
fix humanity with your project Non Nocere.
利用大清洗传播Q波  这招很聪明
And using Myriad to broadcast the Q-waves. That was smart.
但你应该知道
But you should have known the moment
从你决定偷走氪星人东西的那一刻起
you decided to steal from a Kryptonian,
"无害"计划就注定要失败
the Non Nocere was doomed.
卡拉·丹弗斯永远不会以你的方式看问题
Kara Danvers will never see things your way.
她总是和你作对
She'll always work against you.
所以你现在是我的朋友了吗
Right, so you'll be my friend now?
现在世界是我们的了  莉娜
The world is ours now, Lena.
你不需要机器人  也不需要朋友
You don't need a robot and you don't need friends.
你需要一个搭档
You need a partner.
想象一下我们可以一起实现的成就
Imagine what we could accomplish together.
为什么不试试呢
Why not give it a go?
你认为这是你的世界了
So you think this is your world now?
你以前是利维坦的傀儡
You were a puppet on a string for Leviathan before.
这次又有什么不同
What makes this time any different?
利维坦是什么
What the hell is Leviathan?
超 女
第五季 第十集
我想让你知道  我会加倍努力
I want you to know I'll be doubling my efforts
用我的行动来调整我的情绪
to calibrate my emotions with my actions.
也就是买你最喜欢的早餐奶昔
To wit, your favorite breakfast smoothie.
尽管我内心充满了冲动
And despite every urge in my corporeal being,
但我只点了两份
I ordered only two.
谢谢你  布莱尼
Thanks, Brainy.
伙计  我来为巴尼伍号取外卖
My good man, I'm picking up a to-go order for Barney Fife,
-如果有人问起...  -停
- if anyone asks... - Halt.
天呐
Oh, my.
这是什么意思
What? What is the meaning of this?
-什么意思  我不...  -你是谁
- Meaning... I don't-- - Who are you?
-我是布莱尼亚克五号  -什么
- I'm Brainiac-5. - What?
-骗人  -先生
- Liar! - You, sir,
你是个盗窃犯和伪装者
are the larcenist and pretender.
你是怎么做到的
How did you accomplish this ruse?
利用形象诱发器吗
Could it be an image inducer?
是你在伪装  先生
The question of pretending is to you, sir!
你是什么人  火星人  杜兰星人
What are you, huh? Martian, Durlan?
你的脸是粘土做的吗
Is your face made of clay?
放开我  你这个冒牌货
Unhand me, you charlatan!
够了  我要带你去超查部进行审问
Okay, that's it. I'm taking you into the DEO for questioning.
真可笑  你猜怎么着
Okay, that's rich! Guess what,
我要带你去超查部进行审问
I'm taking you into the DEO for questioning.
真可笑
Oh, that's rich...
你被逮捕了
Citizens arrest!
莱克斯·卢瑟和超女打败自由代表
卢瑟兄妹又为罕见疾病找到治疗方法
卢瑟拯救资金短缺的超查部
我一直在找你
I've been looking for you.
我在这里
Here I am.
有件事我得告诉你
So, uh, there's something I have to tell you.
我知道你觉得莱克斯是个好人
I know you think Lex is a good man,
-认为他是你的搭档  -省省吧  我已经知道了
- that he's your partner-- - Save it. I already know.
你到底知道些什么
What exactly do you know?
那场危机  以及莱克斯的所作所为
The Crisis, what Lex did.
-你的所作所为  -莱克斯
- What you did. - Lex.
你出击了
That you took the punch.
你认为过来找我会是什么结果
What did you think would happen when you came here?
你会无私地告诉我一切
That you'd tell me everything in a fit of selflessness,
即使我知道你背叛了我
even if it meant that I knew how you betrayed me,
然后我就会为你倾倒  原谅你
and then I'd just keel over and forgive you.
莉娜  我伤害了你  我...
Lena, I hurt you. I--
我知道我伤害了你
I know I hurt you.
我再也不会这样做了
And I'm never ever going to do it again.
我知道你想为这个世界上做好事
And I know how much good you want to do in the world.
我们可以通过合作来帮助人们
Just think of what we could do together to help people.
有趣
Funny.
莱克斯也跟我说了同样的话
Lex gave me the same pitch.
他让你帮他
He asked you to help him?
你该不会在认真考虑吧
You're not seriously considering it, are you?
拜托  小心点
Please, just be careful.
丹弗斯局长
Director Danvers!
发生了什么事
What is going on?
问得好
Exactly the correct question.
这确实是个悖论
Paradox to be sure.
肯定有个合理的解释
There must be a reasonable explanation.
如果你肯坦白  我们就会得到解释了
And we will get one, once you confess.
我知道我会为问这个问题而后悔
Uh, I know I'm gonna regret asking this question,
你们俩谁才是我的布莱尼
but which of you is my Brainy?
-你怎么能问这个问题  -你怎么能问这个问题
- How can you seriously ask that? - How can you seriously ask that?
这个嘛
Well...
准备好审讯室
Get an interrogation room ready.
抱歉  你是哪位
I'm sorry, who the hell are you?
我是超查部的布莱尼亚克五号局长
I'm Director Brainiac-5 of the DEO.
我才是超查部的局长
I am the Director of the DEO.
为什么大家都在大喊大叫
Why is everyone yelling!
你们是在开玩笑吧
Oh, you have got to be sprocking me!
你们都处在严重的危险之中
You're all in grave danger.
别让他打开...
Don't let him open...
那个瓶子
the bottle.
有人杀了他
Someone killed him?
他成为了目标
He was targeted,
这意味着其他任何一个人都可能成为下一个目标
which means any of the others could be next.
原来你不是在开玩笑
No, you weren't kidding.
是的  谢谢你
No. Thank you.
DNA不会说谎  所以你们都是布莱尼亚克五号
DNA doesn't lie, so you are all Brainiac-5.
这让我想起了赫文星上螃蟹的情况
This reminds me of a situation with some crabs on Helven.
可怕的经历
Terrible experience.
他似乎是被某种生物合成病毒杀死的
He seems to have been killed by some sort of biosynthetic virus.
反生命方程式
The Anti-Life Equation.
抱歉  什么
The... sorry, what?
这是一种高科技有机毒药
It's a techno-organic poison.
它具有针对性  并通过大脑传播
It's targeted and transmitted through the big brain.
真的很可怕  伙计
It's really scary, man!
我从未听说过这种东西
I've never heard of such a thing.
你就是布莱尼本体吧
We're supposed to believe that you're the Brainy Prime?
这是真的  他是我们的布莱尼
Well, it's true. He's ours.
那么这就不是我们的世界了
Well, then this can't be our world.
这意味着我们一定穿过了某种...
Which means we must have stumbled through some sort of...
空间虫洞
Dimensional wormhole.
来自不同的宇宙
From our different universes.
虫洞  宇宙
Wormhole... Universes, yeah.
抱歉  伙计们  我们遇到了一场小小危机
I'm sorry, guys, there's a slight crisis--
唯一合理的前进路线
The only logical path forward
就是找到我们到达的连接点
is to find the nexus point of our arrival,
只有这样才能弄清楚我们是怎么来到这里的
if we're ever to ascertain how it is we came to be here,
为什么我们死去的同志会警告我们有严重的危险
why our deceased comrade warned us we're in grave danger?
他劝我们不要打开的那个瓶子是什么
What that bottle was he urged us not to open?
之后  我们就可以安全返回各自的地球
After which, we can all safely return to our respective Earths.
同意
Agreed.
是的  只是你们不能回到你们的地球
Yes, except you can't return to your Earths
因为多元宇宙已经没了
because the multi-verse is dead.
-所以...  -布莱尼
- So. - Brainy.
好吧  我说话太直了
All right. That is insensitive.
什么  多元宇宙没了
What? The multi-verse, it's dead?
除非有不为人知的
Unless there's a vibrational frequency henceforth
振动频率  否则...
unknown to man, then...
我们的宇宙就是仅剩的宇宙了
our universe is the only one that's left.
抱歉打扰了
Apologies for the interruption,
丹弗斯局长和超女
but would Director Danvers and Supergirl,
请立即到会议室报到
please report to the conference room immediately?
你想要什么  莱克斯
What do you want, Lex?
-和平  -这是不可能的
- Peace. - It's never gonna happen.
我明白
Look, I get it,
这感觉有点恶心
feels icky,
但我们为什么不换个角度想想呢
but why don't we think about it in another way?
为什么要开战  把事情搞得一团糟
Why go to war and make things messy,
我们明明可以下一盘舒服的棋
when we could all play a comfortable game of chess?
你可以盯着我  我也可以盯着你
You could keep an eye on me, I could keep an eye on you,
与此同时  世界将拥有它最喜欢的英雄
and in the meantime, the world would have its favorite heroes
肩并肩地抵御威胁
standing shoulder to shoulder to keep threats
比如反监视者和利维坦
like the Anti-Monitor and Leviathan at bay.
那些家伙到底怎么样了  有传言吗
Say, what's happening with those guys anyway? Any rumblings?
反监视者消失了
The Anti-Monitor is gone.
自从多元宇宙崩塌之后
And we haven't found a trace of Leviathan
我们还没有找到利维坦的踪迹
since the multi-verse collapsed. So...
所以这个世界唯一的威胁就是你
So the only threat to this world is you.
听到这个消息我很难过
I'm sorry to hear that.
花一天时间好好想想
Look, take a day to think it over.
如果你选择和平
And if you choose peace,
我希望你在"明日之人"颁奖礼上
I'll expect you by my side,
能公开地站在我身边
publicly, at the Man of Tomorrow ceremony.
如果你不那么做
But if you don't,
我想我们会遭遇更多的大灾难
I suppose we'll have a little more apocalypse.
82%使用手机套餐的顾客
Eighty-two percent of customers
已经购买了我们的VR附加组件
with cell phone plans have purchased our VR add-on.
但我们可以做得更好
But we can still do better.
我们需要让每个美国家庭都用上黑曜石
We need to get Obsidian into every American household,
我们已经很接近目标了
and we are so close.
确实很接近
Quite close, indeed.
真没想到会见到你
Wha-- what a pleasant surprise!
你好
Hello!
各位  这是杰玛·库珀
Team, this is Gemma Cooper,
我们的董事会成员之一  也是我敬爱的大学导师
one of our board members and my beloved college mentor.
散会  谢谢
That's all. Thank you.
好了  这需要一些技术操作
Okay, it took some technical doing,
但我想我已经证实了...
but I believe I've confirmed that--
只有我们几位布莱尼亚克五号穿过了虫洞
We are the only Brainiac-5s that came through the wormhole,
你现在查到阿尔酒吧了
which you've now traced to Al's Bar.
我们也是  几分钟前推断出来的
Yeah, we, too, deduced that several moments ago,
但是阿尔酒吧
but hey, Al's bar,
我真的很喜欢他家的无酒精玛格丽特
I do love their margarita mocktails.
也许我们应该去
Perhaps we should go...
别别别别别
Oh! No, no, no, no, no.
本体  帮我找出病毒
Prime, help me root out the virus.
怎么找  我不...
How? Uh, I don't...
没事  没事  有我在
Okay. It's okay. That's okay. I got you.
没事了
Here we go.
好了
Okay.
我刚才差点死掉
You know, I could have died just there.
谢谢你的犹豫不决
Thanks to your hesitancy.
我们该相信他是布莱尼亚克五号吗
We're supposed to believe that he's a Brainiac-5!
朋友们  朋友们  专心点
Friends, friends, focus.
这种病毒有可能从任何地方传播
The virus is transmittable from anywhere.
下一个有可能是我们其中一人
Any one of us could be next.
你待在这
You, stay here.
我们会去阿尔酒吧查个水落石出的
We'll head down to Al's Bar. We'll get to the bottom of this.
-好  -他走了
- Okay. - There he goes.
帅气  看着他走的样子
Handsome. Look at him go.
我去找超女
I'll go get Supergirl.
这里怎么回事
Hey, what's going on here...
阿尔
Al's.
昨晚大家突然都来了
Everybody just showed up out of the blue last night.
生意好得不得了
Business has never been better.
我不得不把后面的房间也打开了
I had to open up the back room.
这地方一直都存在吗
Has this place always been here?
是的  79年迪斯科不流行后  我就关了
Yup. I closed it in '79 after disco died.
你多大了
How old are you?
不过这些人也带来了很多东西
These guys brought a ton of stuff with them, though.
-你们落了什么吗  -好玩
- You guys missing anything? - What fun!
不管虫洞是什么原因造成的
Look, whatever caused that wormhole
不仅把我们卷了进去
didn't just drag us through,
还把我们每个宇宙的阿尔酒吧的人也卷进去了
it dragged everyone from Al's bar in each of our universes.
天啊  那些是...
Oh, dear. Are those...
不要做任何突然的动作
Don't make any sudden movements.
那些是创造出主宰的女巫
Those are the witches that created Reign.
并且试图改造我们整个星球
And tried to terraform our entire planet.
那些不是你们的女巫
Those aren't your witches.
她们是我的同乡
They come from my world.
她们作为游客来到纳欣诺市  就再没离开过
They came to National City as tourists and never left.
我让她们在酒吧里打打杂
I let them run a little side hustle out of the bar.
来吧  我的孩子们
Come forth, my children.
来算算命
Have your fortune read.
我宁愿避免这种不可靠的预测机制
I prefer to avoid such unreliable forecasting mechanisms.
水晶球  好笑
Crystals balls! Ha-ha.
比傻瓜的金子更真实
A lot more real than fool's gold.
让我来看看你们的宝石
Allow me to read your stones.
请原谅我姐姐
Please, forgive my sisters.
看手相是预知命运的最快捷径
Palm reading is the fastest path to your fate.
十分钟五块钱
Five dollars, ten minutes.
不了  谢谢
No, thank you.
-随便你  -让人失望
- Suit yourself. - Typical.
这个地球上没人重视我们的天赋
No one on this Earth values our gifts.
这个酒吧里的人  他们的地球都毁灭了
Everyone in this bar came from an Earth that was destroyed.
他们都是孤儿
They're all orphans.
太悲催了
That's terrible.
不  超女
No, Supergirl!
整个多元宇宙都毁灭了
The entire multi-verse was destroyed.
命运的安排让我们和这些人一起活了下来
An accident of fate kept us and these people alive.
这不是悲剧
This isn't a tragedy.
而是  而是奇迹
It's a, you know, it's a miracle.
我们要逐个击破
Okay, we need to divide and conquer.
请尽量融入人群
And please, try to blend in,
因为凶手尚未绳之以法
because there is still a murderer out there
你们俩还有危险  好吗
and both of you are still in danger. Okay?
很好
Good.
卢瑟基金会
没想到我能活到这一天
I never thought I'd live to see the day
见证我妈穿花瓣粉色
my mother wore petal pink.
严格来说  你看不到
Technically, you didn't.
我们都死了  又都回来了
We all died. We all came back.
我们俩都知道
And we both know it.
莱克斯也恢复了你的记忆
Lex restored your memories, too.
他把所有的事都告诉我了
He told me everything.
但是显然
But, evidently,
他之所以和神打交道都是为了你
the only person he makes deals with gods for is you.
很高兴他告诉了你一切
I'm glad he told you everything.
我身边已经没人了
I have no one else.
希望你不是来寻求安慰的
I hope you're not looking for a hug.
不  但我觉得我需要一个搭档
No. But it occurred to me I could use a partner.
如果莱克斯把所有的事都告诉你了
If Lex told you everything,
那他告诉你我的目标是从内心去解救人
then he told you my goal was to fix people at their core.
我试过一个人去做
I tried to do it alone.
我封闭自己  隔离自己  但失败了
I closed myself off, made myself an island, and I failed.
你将人拒之门外  选择相信机器人
You pushed people away and put all your faith in that robot.
让我想起北极熊小姐
Reminds me of little Miss Pizzly.
你四岁时的泰迪熊
Your teddy bear from when you were four.
可爱但毫无用处
Cute and useless.
我们都知道你的观念对我没用
We both know your ideology is of no use to me.
我在这里过得很好
I've got a good thing going here.
既然如此
Well, in that case...
超女想要和我搭档
Supergirl wants to partner with me.
我内心有点想要接受
Part of me wants to do it.
这次你可以试试只做搭档
You can try to only be partners this time,
但在你软弱的时候
but in a moment of weakness,
你会放下戒心  会再一次变成她的朋友
you'll let your guard down, you'll become friends once more,
而当她再次伤害你的时候  你又会脆弱不堪
and you'll be vulnerable when she hurts you all over again.
然而  你并不想自我封闭
And yet, you don't want to be an island.
是的
No.
我再也不会再相信莱克斯了
I will never trust Lex again.
如果你选择和莱克斯一起搭档
If you choose to partner with Lex,
你不会拿自己的情绪冒险
you won't risk your emotions,
因为你已经知道你永远也不会相信他
because you already know you can never trust him.
我要向莱克斯·卢瑟汇报
I report to Lex Luthor.
这是最糟的情况
This is worst-case scenario.
我不知道我要怎么在他手下做事
I don't know how I'm supposed to work for him,
而且我们都知道他就是个定时炸弹
and yet we all know that he's this bomb
随时都会爆炸
that could just blow at any minute.
我真的可以离开吗
So, I mean, can I even really leave?
早在我招募你之前
You know, long before I recruited you,
一个叫依奇的外星人遭到她的同事绑架
an alien named Izzy was held captive by her co-worker.
然后他发现了她的真面目
Now, he'd found out what she really was
无法控制自己的怒火
and couldn't control his rage.
依奇自然是吓坏了
Izzy was naturally terrified.
但因为袭击她的是人类
But because her attacker was human,
超查部没有管辖权
the DEO didn't have jurisdiction.
那时的情况和现在不一样
Things were different back then.
我当时感到很无助
I felt so helpless.
那你是怎么做的
So what did you do?
我知道我必须采取行动
What I knew I had to do.
我违反了上级命令
I disobeyed orders.
跑到那里  把那个人制服在地上
Ran in there and tackled that man to the ground myself.
有时你只能听从
Sometimes there's nothing to do
自己内心的真实想法  艾丽克斯
but listen to the truth inside you, Alex.
荣誉在于你跑向炸弹的那一刻
The honor comes in running toward the bomb.
墙上有762瓶啤酒
Seven hundred and sixty-two bottles of beer on the wall.
但却毫无线索
And they're all completely lacking in clues.
又在自言自语
Talking to yourself.
如果你愿意的话  可以跟我聊聊
You can talk to me instead, if you'd like.
毕竟我就是你
I'm you, after all.
你无视了我们一整天  现在倒想聊了
Ignored us all day, and now you want to talk.
我看到你了
I see you.
每个转角你都比我们慢一步
You've been one step behind the rest of us at every turn.
你跟我们有什么不同
What is making you different?
倒是没什么大不了  不过...
It's not a big deal or anything, but
我戴着...
I do wear...
-性格抑制器  -我就知道
- Personality inhibiters. - I knew it.
你为什么要戴这个
Why would you wear those?
-为了保护  -保护
- For protection. - Protection?
性格抑制器会让你
Personality inhibitors block you
无法与大脑交流
from engaging with the big brain.
能够阻止你感受真实的自我
They stop you from accessing your true self.
你真正的潜力  你真正的快乐
Your true potential, your true happiness.
你不会觉得前后相悖吗
Don't you ever feel inconsistent?
不确定  无法平衡理性和感性
Uncertain? Unable to balance logic and emotion?
瞧瞧你的样子  你甚至都不是绿色的
I mean, look at you, you're not even green.
好吧  那愤怒呢
Okay, sure. And what about the anger?
那种怒火
The rage?
我戴这些不是为了保护自己
I don't wear these to protect myself!
是为了保护我爱的人
I wear them to protect the people I love.
在我的故乡  我结婚了
Where I'm from, I was married.
和她在一起时  我更强大  更聪明  更优秀
I was stronger, smarter, better, every moment I was with her.
-你失去她了吗  -没有
- You lost her? - No.
她还在我身边
She's with me.
她活在大脑里
She lives on in the big brain.
当我在这里的工作完成后  我也会去那里
Just as I will, when my work here is finished.
我想说的是  爱不会限制你
What I'm saying is love is not meant to minimize you.
反而会让你更完整
It makes you more.
更强大  更有同情心
More capable. More compassionate.
而那些真正爱你的人们
And the people who really love you,
他们不希望你这样
they don't want this for you.
谢谢你说这么多  科·艾尔
I appreciate the chat, Kor-El,
但我觉得自己现在这样很有能力
but I feel very capable as I am.
那随你吧
Suit yourself.
从头到尾都只是个全息投影
A hologram, this whole time.
我现在知道这样有多没礼貌了
Now I see how rude that is.
我一直以为我们那位布莱尼独一无二
I always thought my Brainy was one of a kind.
抱歉  我是尼娅
I'm sorry, I'm Nia.
我的布莱尼跟我说了所有的事
My Brainy filled me in on everything
而我必须来亲自看一眼
and I just had to see you all for myself.
我带了午餐  你饿了吗
I brought lunch. You hungry?
不  抱歉
No, I... sorry.
我现在想一个人待着
I just wanna be alone right now.
他还提到了一个瓶子的事
He also said something about a bottle.
一个瓶子
A bottle.
好吧
Alas...
你真是把我抓了个现行
You have caught me in the act.
但我很开心
But I'm glad.
这种表演
The act was
让我心累
emotionally exhausting.
瓶子里是什么
What's in the bottle?
我的地球上的七十亿条生命
Seven billion souls on my Earth.
都在这里了
All here.
从源头装瓶
Bottled at the source.
在反物质波来临之前的片刻
Moments before the antimatter wave came.
不再等待
No more waiting.
甜蜜的释放
Sweet release.
你把你的世界装瓶了
You bottled your world.
我拯救了他们
I saved them.
阻止了一场种族灭绝
Prevented genocide.
困在静止状态中  还算是真正的生命吗
Now, stuck in stasis, is that truly life?
或者这只是
Or is it just
某种令人厌恶的丑陋死亡
some hideous form of distasteful death?
不如我们上楼吧
Why don't we take it upstairs?
可以在那里进行这些哲学争论
We can hash out the philosophy there.
没什么可争论的
There is nothing to hash.
世上只有生存
There is only life.
和死亡
And death.
比如另外一个布莱尼亚克五号
Take the other Brainiac-5.
他想阻止我打开这个瓶子  于是我杀了他
He tried to prevent me from opening this bottle, so I killed him.
那就是死亡
Death!
等我找到
But once I find the device
打开瓶子的工具
with which to open this bottle,
就能生存
life...
布莱尼
Brainy!
尼娅
Nia.
不
No!
尼娅
Nia.
他利用了布莱尼本体的性格抑制器
He was piggybacking off Brainy Prime's personality inhibitors
迷惑大脑  隐藏他的真实目的
to confuse the big brain and disguise his true intentions.
他的真实目的是什么
What were his intentions?
他缩小了他的整个地球
He shrunk his entire Earth.
然后装瓶了
He bottled it.
缩小和收集世界的做法明显来自慧核星
The shrinking and collection of worlds is distinctly Coluan.
那是我们先祖经常做的事情
It's a terribly common practice among our ancestors.
但是这个布莱尼把世界装瓶是为了保护它吗
But this Brainy bottled his world to protect it?
对  但他如果把他的地球释放出来
Yeah, but if he releases his Earth,
两个地球都会被毁掉
both Earths will be destroyed.
但他打不开瓶子
But he couldn't open the bottle.
没错  所有瓶子都用量子能级以下的方法封死了
Indeed, all bottles are sealed beneath the quantum level to--
为了防止逃离
Prevent escape.
瓶子只能用消耗氩44的的工具打开
Bottles can only be opened using a device that harnesses Argonium 44.
他一定是知道氩光剑
He must have known the Argonium Saber
储存在超查部这里
would be held here at the DEO.
据我所知  那把光剑
That saber is the only one
是太阳系里仅有的一把
that I am aware of in the solar system.
已经被我毁掉了  这为我们争取了一点时间
And I destroyed it, so that bought us some time.
布莱尼
Brainy.
很了不起
It's incredible.
就像在月球上一样
It's like being on the moon.
只是没有失重的感觉
Except for the lack of gravity.
那个我们还在想办法
We're still figuring that out.
但是目前进展神速
But we're making incredible progress.
这进步不只是家家户户都使用黑曜石科技
Progress isn't just Obsidian being in every household.
而是黑曜石中有家家户户
It's about every household being in Obsidian.
-什么意思  -我问你个问题
- What do you mean? - Tell me something.
如果你从未为你父亲工作过
If you never had to work for your father,
安德里亚·罗哈斯现在想成为怎样的人
what would Andrea Rojas want to be right now?
人类学家
An anthropologist.
我很喜欢
Oh, I love it.
你可以住在错综复杂的大庄园
You can live on a sprawling hacienda,
旁边是你最新的阿兹特克人挖掘点
close to your latest Aztec dig site.
-这个梦很美  -这不是梦
- It's a pleasant dream. - Not a dream.
是现实  在真实的虚拟世界里
A reality. In a true virtual world.
当有人拿着你找到的遗物时
When someone holds an artifact that you found,
能够亲手感受到它的重量
they feel its weight in their actual hand.
想象一个全新的世界
Imagine a whole new world,
为受到伤害的人
a whole new reality for
提供全新的现实
harmed and damaged people.
他们可以过上梦想中的生活
They can live their dream lives.
最终  他们可以留在那里
And eventually, they could stay there.
永远留在那里
Indefinitely.
一个群居世界
A collective of being.
真正的虚拟世界会改变一切
A true virtual world will change the game.
我怎么跟你说的
What do I always tell you?
必须做出改变
You gotta move the needle.
有了这个
And with this...
我们的股价能翻倍
Our share prices could double.
布莱尼  停  你不用...
Brainy, stop. You don't have to...
我八岁的时候
When I was eight years old,
我一家人去...
my family went on...
按你们人类的说法  是去度假
what humans might call a vacation.
那是我第一次看见雪
This was the first time I had seen the snow.
太不可思议了
It was incredible.
你跟我说这个干什么
Why are you telling me this?
因为我妈妈看出来  我有多喜欢雪
'Cause my mother saw how much I loved it.
我多么...
How badly I...
想就那样待在雪里
I wanted to stay there in the snow.
她就把雪装在瓶子里送给了我
And so, she bottled it for me.
-连带着整个星球  -布莱尼
- The entire planet. - Brainy...
我爸爸知道之后很震惊
My father was horrified at what she had done.
他释放了那个星球
He freed the planet.
我还太小  当时我很生气
I was so young and angry with him...
因为他夺走了我的星球
for taking away my planet.
我的星球
My planet!
我的怒气把他吓坏了
And that anger terrified him.
他担心我的内心也会滋生黑暗
He feared that I, too, could hold such darkness within me.
变成我妈妈那样
That I could become my mother.
就在我身上放了三个性格抑制器
So he placed three personality inhibitors on me.
我一直戴到今天
The same ones I wear to this very day.
你的三颗点
Your three dots.
戴着的时候  我和慧核星意识网络
When I wear them, I'm not fully calibrated
也就是主脑之间的联系不准确
with the Coluan network of minds, the big brain.
要是我没戴的话
If I hadn't been wearing them,
坏布莱尼就不会骗到我们了
that bad Brainy wouldn't have been able to fool us.
你害怕摘下来吗
And you're afraid to take them off?
因为我可能会更糟糕  而尼娅她...
Because I might be worse. And Nia, she...
她可能就不喜欢我了
She might not care for me.
布莱尼  你的善良是发自内心的
Brainy, you are good to your core.
你永远不会成为你母亲那样的人
You will never be your mother.
-你怎么能确定  -因为有人爱你
- How could you be sure? - Because you're loved.
爱你的人一定会为了你而努力
And the people that love you will always fight for you.
谢谢你  卡拉
Thank you, Kara.
你的话语能给人带来希望和安慰
Your ability to instill hope and comfort with your words is...
就像魔法一样
is nothing short of magic.
-魔法  -女巫能打开瓶子
- Magic. - The witches can open the bottle.
他去阿尔酒吧了
He's going to Al's.
我们必须通知其他的布莱尼
We have to tell the other Brainys.
不  我  我得一个人面对
No, I, I need to do this alone.
-但你也应该去  -我这就去
- But you should come, too. - I'm coming.
你为什么帮他
Why are you helping him?
你本可以在这里过安稳的日子
You could have a peaceful life here.
危机把我们带去一个陌生的世界
The Crisis brought us to a strange world.
如果慧核星人成功了  就能带我们回去
If the Coluan is successful, he will return us home.
就为了打开瓶子  不值得冒那个险
Opening that bottle isn't worth the risk.
值得
Yes, it is.
所有人都可能会死
You could kill everyone.
如果其他地球都消亡了
Why should this Earth live,
地球凭什么独活
when every other died?
因为我们只剩这一个地球了
'Cause it's the only one we've got left!
别废话了
Enough talk.
很久没好好打一场了
It's been ages since we had a good bar fight.
等等
Wait!
我们不能改变过去
We can't undo the past.
瞧好了
Watch us.
布莱尼
Brainy.
都是我的错
This is all my fault.
布莱尼  没事的
Brainy, it's okay.
你可以摘下来
You can take them off.
万一我变成...
But what if I turn...
无论如何  我都爱你
No matter what happens, I love you.
不  不要
No, don't!
我知道你失去了你的全世界
I know you lost your whole world,
你的朋友  你的家
your friends, your home.
我也怀念我曾拥有的一切
I miss what I had, too.
我完全能够理解你
I know what you're going through.
你觉得那都是你的责任
How responsible you must feel.
你什么都不知道
You don't know anything!
可我都知道  因为我就是你
But I know everything because I'm you.
我也能感受到黑暗的力量
I feel the darkness, too.
你做过错误的决定  但那些决定并不能定义你
You've made some bad choices, but they don't have to define you.
我失去了一切
I lost everything.
现在做出不同的决定  还来得及
It's not too late to make a different choice.
让我们帮你
Let us help you.
我和我的朋友  我们都很聪明
My friends and I, we're pretty smart.
我们一定能找到安全的地方  打开你的瓶子
Together, we can find a safe place to open your bottle
不伤害其他人
without hurting anyone.
那个精明的家伙说得对
The suave one is right.
风险太大了
It is too much of a risk.
但如果我们给这些人一个机会
But if we give these people a chance,
他们说不定哪天就找到送我们回家的办法了
they may find a way of returning us home one day.
我们只要等就好了
All we can do is wait for that day.
但你不用一个人等
But you don't have to wait alone,
我们陪你一起
we can wait with you.
超女和梦想者
Supergirl and Dreamer are
会把瓶子带到堡垒  以防万一
bringing the bottle to the fortress for safekeeping.
这样就能处理那个游荡的布莱尼亚克五号了
Which solves the problem of one errant Brainiac-5.
我们也这么想
We were thinking that, too.
人像投影
Life projectors.
虽然我们的世界不在了
Our worlds may be gone,
但主脑还在
but the big brain remains.
在这个数据云里
A digital cloud where
多克斯女士和我可以放弃我们的躯体
Ms. Dox and I can relinquish our corporeal forms
活在慧核星的知识储备里
and live amongst the Coluan knowledge aggregate.
-你不必这么做的  -我想这么做
- You don't have to do that. - We want to.
我们或许失去了自己的世界
We may have lost our worlds,
但在主脑内生存的感觉就像...
but existing inside of the big brain will feel like...
回到了家
like going home.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢你们
Both of you.
谢谢你们做的一切
For everything.
谢谢你  布莱尼亚克五号
Thank you, Brainiac-5,
抱歉  之前拿你的奶昔
and, uh, sorry for trying to take your smoothie.
感觉好奇怪
What a strange sensation.
有件事情要告诉你
There's something you need to know.
我留你们两个独自面对今天的威胁
The reason I left the two of you to face today's threat alone
是因为我一直在检测莱克斯·卢瑟的行动
is because I've been tracking Lex Luthor's every move.
他一直在向堡垒询问
He's been calling the archive
某种信息  就是利维坦
for information on only one thing, Leviathan.
利维坦已经被击败了
Leviathan is defeated.
利维坦无处不在
Leviathan is everywhere.
我们两个世界的时间线是最接近的
The timeline of our worlds is closer than any other.
事件都在同一条轨迹上展开
Events progress on the same path.
你决不能跟我犯同样的错
You must not make the same mistakes I made.
我跟莱克斯·卢瑟对着干
I fought against Lex Luthor,
结果引发了难以想象的灾难
and it led to catastrophe beyond imagining.
整个世界都危在旦夕
It endangered the entire world.
你要想拯救世界
If you're gonna save your world,
就得和莱克斯·卢瑟合作
you have to work with Lex Luthor.
我会告诉你你需要知道的一切
I'll show you everything you need to know.
我会告诉你我在我的世界
I'll show you everything I did
做错了什么  事情变得有多糟糕
wrong in my world, how bad things became.
但是科·艾尔
But Kor-El.
科·艾尔  你必须独自行动
Kor-El, you must do this alone.
没人能知道你在做这件事
No one can know that you're doing this.
你必须放弃你所珍视的一切
You must give up everyone and everything that you hold dear.
甚至是尼娅
Even Nia?
直到世界被拯救
Till the world has been saved.
对不起
I'm sorry.
科·艾尔
Kor-El,
你永远不会孤独
you'll never truly be alone.
我会与你同行
I will be with you.
你不是要参加什么仪式吗
Aren't you supposed to be at a ceremony or something?
成功若不和他人分享
Success isn't worth much
便毫无价值
if you don't have anyone to share it with.
我一直想和你分享我的胜利  妹妹
I always wanted to share my victories with you, sis.
甚至去年的卡兹尼亚计划我都找你入伍
Even last year, with the Kasnians, I brought you in.
那不算什么吗
Doesn't that count for anything?
一时的体贴
One moment of thoughtfulness
能弥补多年的背叛吗  不能
to make up for years of betrayal? No.
我知道你有许多理由不信任我
I know you have plenty of reasons to distrust me,
但你不知道那种感受
but you don't know what it's like to...
死亡
die.
当你预见死亡来临时  那种令人作呕的绝望
The sickening desperation when you see it coming for you.
让我想要大发雷霆
It made me want to lash out.
让我想要伤害你
It made me want to hurt you.
就像我伤害你一样
Like I hurt you.
你杀了我  但这不是我想说的
Killed me. But that's exactly my point.
死亡确实改变了我
Death truly has changed me.
以前的我会幻想着
The old me would be dreaming of
无数种报复你的方式
the myriad ways I could exact my revenge on you,
但如今的我
but the new me
看得出那是多么可悲无趣
can see how pathetically pedestrian that is.
我终于准备好做一个真正的搭档了  莉娜
I'm finally ready to be a true partner, Lena.
我要怎么相信你
How am I supposed to believe you?
你是个反社会者  是个骗子
You were a sociopath, a liar.
你需要的是真相
What you need is the truth.
求真者让我无法说谎
The Truth Seeker will prevent me from lying.
所以  妹妹你想知道什么
So, sis, what do you want to know?
你能帮我完成无害计划吗
Can you help me achieve Non Nocere?
比其他人更快更好
Better and faster than anybody else.
你真的会好好表现吗  不杀人
Will you truly be on your best behavior? No homicides?
不杀不必要的人
No unnecessary homicides.
这件事不是为了伤害别人
This is about doing no harm.
但我不会
But I won't.
除了你的配合  我已万事俱备
I have everything I want except for your partnership.
你什么时候会背叛我
When will you turn on me?
一旦我们的合作关系威胁到我
As soon as this partnership inconveniences me.
就像你一旦有机会就会
Just like you'll use Non Nocere
用无害计划对付我
on me as soon as you get the chance.
很好  看来我们彼此都很清楚
Good. As long as we're clear.
你不需要我  你为什么想要和我合作
You don't need me. Why do you really want to work with me?
说实话
Truthfully,
我不想独自一人
I don't want to be alone.
-你好  -你好
- Hey. - Hello.
你感觉怎么样
How do you feel?
-毫无禁忌  -差不多吧
- Uninhibited? - Something like that.
我很高兴
You know, I'm really glad
看到能够舒服地做自己
to see you so comfortable in your own skin.
我一直以来只想要你
It's all I ever really wanted for you
能够做自己
was to be able to be yourself.
我现在就是如此
And now I am.
我能感受到  通过我的身体
I can feel it, all through my body.
通过我的指尖
The tips of my fingers.
但有些事情现在需要改变  尼娅
And now, some things are gonna have to change, Nia.
当然  布莱尼  无论你需要什么
Of course. Look, Brainy, whatever you need,
我们都会解决的
we'll work it out.
我们一起
Together.
一起  那是
Together... that's...
那才是需要改变的东西
That's what has to change.
-什么  -我不能和你在一起了
- What? - I can't be with you anymore.
我不理解
I don't understand.
你是谁
Who are you?
有史以来第一次
For the first time, ever,
我是我自己
myself.
欢迎大家的到来
Welcome, everyone.
我很高兴今晚能够在这里
It gives me great pleasure to be here tonight.
你在这里做什么
Hey, what are you doing over here?
我只是
I just, uh...
我知道你会觉得我疯了
Look, I know you're gonna think I'm crazy,
但我觉得莱克斯·卢瑟不是他说的那样
but I'm not so sure Lex Luthor is what he says he is.
-什么  -几个好人同心协力
- What? - with the deeds of just a few good people...
我以为你和其他人一样都很喜欢他
I thought you loved him like everyone else.
我还在《泰晤士报》时
While I was still at The Times in London,
莱克斯试图收购我朋友  罗素·罗杰斯的公司
Lex tried to buy my friend, Russell Roger's company.
罗素拒绝了  结果死了
Russell refused and ended up dead.
我觉得莱克斯·卢瑟是幕后黑手
I think Lex Luthor was behind it.
你有任何实质性证据吗
Do you have any concrete evidence?
还没有
Not yet.
所以我才来凯特科工作
That's why I applied to work at CatCo,
为了接近莉娜·卢瑟
to get closer to Lena Luthor,
但她却把公司卖给了安德里亚
but then she sold the company to Andrea,
现在我需要你的帮助
and now, I could use your help.
总得有人保护世界不受卢瑟一家的危害
Someone has to protect the world from the Luthors.
不是卢瑟一家  是莱克斯
Not the Luthors, Lex.
我知道莉娜  她和别人一样都面临危险
I know Lena. She's in just as much danger as everyone else.
贵宾和我
The guest of honor and I
在过去一同取得了许多成就
have already accomplished so much in the past.
我很期待
And I'm looking forward
看到我们未来的辉煌成果
to seeing what we will achieve in the future.
她之前倾向和氪星人合作
She was leaning towards the Kryptonian.
-不用谢  -你对我太好了
- You're welcome. - You're too good to me.
我们统治前世时曾是伙伴
We were partners when we took over the last world...
女士们  先生们  允许我向你们介绍
Ladies and gentlemen, allow me to introduce...
我们为什么不能在今世仍是伙伴呢
...why shouldn't we be partners in this one, too?
我的哥哥  我的伙伴
...my brother, my partner,
莱克斯·卢瑟  明日之子
Lex Luthor, the Man of Tomorrow.
需要帮忙吗  多克斯特工
Oh, how can I help you, Agent Dox?
我的朋友会与你为敌
My friends will work against you.
你知道  我也知道
You know it. I know it.
但是他们目光短浅
But they're shortsighted.
真正的威胁
The true threat. The...
唯一的威胁仍是利维坦
The only threat that matters is Leviathan.
我想要帮你击败他们
I'd like to help you defeat them.
好
Well...
很高兴听你这么说
that's good to hear.
但是在这个新世界仍没有
But no information about Leviathan exists
利维坦存在的证据
in this new world...
在这个时空
at this time.
我需要未来的知识
I need knowledge from the future.
我有理由相信
I have reason to believe a
有个二重身穿过虫洞来到了这里
particular doppelganger came through the wormhole.
他已经被逮捕  但我们如果合理出招
He's already been arrested, but if we play our cards right,
就可以获取未来
we can bring the future to us.